RELAND BOYLE

Software Engineer

+1 (631) 806-0019 • reland.boyle@gmail.com • New York, NY • linkedin.com/in/relandboyle • github.com/relandboyle

SUMMARY

Software engineer and generalist with 15+ years of varied professional experience across product development, mechanical design, project management, customer success, and full stack software development. Working in three mainstream programming languages and four frameworks. Known for rapidly becoming a subject matter expert, mentor, and trusted source of information.

SKILLS

JavaScript • TypeScript • Java • Dart • Angular • React • Spring • Flutter • D3 • RxJS • Node • Express • Docker • Kubernetes • OpenShift • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Firebase • Material UI • Angular Material • Flutter Material • CSS/Sass/Less • Electron • AWS • Linode • Linux • OAuth • Auth0 • Grafana • Prometheus • Git/GitHub • BitBucket •

Work Experience

Citigroup - Senior Software Engineer, Frontend

May 2022 - Present

- Revamped hiring process for engineers, resulting in a 20% improvement in efficiency and code quality across the organization; introduced technical skills assessments and conducted in-depth behavioral interviews to identify high-performing candidates
- Reinvented hiring assessments for React and Angular developers, creating work simulations to test 1000+ candidates annually
- Transformed 20+ FE/BE engineers into Full Stack engineers as a Subject Matter Expert in TypeScript/Angular and Java/Spring
- Built an internal tool providing interactive D3 force-directed graphs with physics simulation to display microservice topology

DataCaliper - NetSuite Developer

November 2021 - March 2022

- Integrated SuiteScript 2.0 programs within SuiteCloud Developer Framework to customize NetSuite instances for multiple clients
- Produced Advanced PDF Templates, Workflows, and Formula Fields to reduce wait times and cognitive load by up to 60%
- Typically responded to client requests within 24 hours with effective, creative solutions and delivered within 5 business days

Rich Brilliant Willing - Assistant Director of Operations

January 2016 - August 2021

- Optimized processes across departments, automating repetitive tasks and implementing integrations between Oracle NetSuite ERP/CRM and 4 secondary platforms, working with tech such as NetSuite Workflows and SuiteScript Developer Framework
- Achieved 100% product compliance with relevant consumer product safety standards and internal performance standards
- Founded and managed RBW's Customer Success Team, hired CSR's, established metrics and service level agreements, reduced post-sale support cases from 15% to 5% of all sales while mentoring team members and generating internal tech wiki
- Routinely directed \$1M+ custom lighting projects through ideation, design, compliance, manufacturing, delivery, and installation

Recent Projects

Drone Tools React, **Drone Tools Angular**

April 2022 - November 2022

- Developed a single-page React/TypeScript application to calculate multirotor aircraft propeller tip speed relative to local Mach 1
- Completely rebuilt the application using Angular 13, RxJS Observables and operators, Reactive Forms, and Angular Material
- Employed Netlify/AWS Lambda serverless functions to mask sensitive data in server calls from the client to the API
- Introduced SCSS style sheets to achieve a responsive, mobile-friendly design that renders gracefully on displays up to 4k

Skills Grid

January 2022 - February 2022

- Constructed a full-stack JavaScript CRUD application to assist over 500 recent boot camp graduates in the first tech job search
- Deployed a Node/Express server and a vanilla JS (ES21) frontend relying on DOM manipulation and a MondoDB Atlas instance
- Authored 7+ modular LESS style sheets to provide consistent styling and transitions while writing more maintainable CSS

KR8S for Kubernetes

September 2021 - November 2021

- Created a React/Electron single-page desktop dashboard application to visualize and monitor Kubernetes cluster health and
 performance metrics, providing developers with real-time insight into the impact of changes made to the deployed application,
 accelerating the development lifecycle and reducing the need to review and respond to logs by up to 75% during development
- Automated deployment of a React/Express test application via multiple Docker containers in a local Kubernetes cluster with preconfigured Prometheus servers feeding Grafana dashboards for a 60% reduction in environment setup time for new users

EDUCATION

- Codesmith Residency for Software Engineers Syllabus
- Dassault Systemes Certified SolidWork Certificate
- Suffolk Aviation Academy Private Pilot

August 2021 - November 2021 January 2020 - June 2020

September 1994 - June 1996

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Career Support Engineer for Codesmith Alumni
- Tech Talks Sponsored by Single Sprout: <u>User Experience Best Practices</u>

February 2022 - present

October 2021